<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com"/>

  <title>Devin Halladay</title>
  <link href="http://devinhalladay.com"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://devinhalladay.com/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2013-10-20T00:02:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://devinhalladay.com</id>
  <author>
    <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    <email>devin@devinhalladay.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designed-with-love</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designed-with-love"/>
    <title>Designed with Love</title>
    <published>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;I love design. Its uncanny ability to make any person feel a wide range of emotions is absolutely fascinating. As designers, we hold the power of emotion in our hands — we can use color theory to evoke emotions, whitespace to draw attention, and so much more. That fact makes it clear that we need to pay attention to every pixel and give an equal amount of care to every single detail in what we are designing, in order to honestly and efficiently harness emotion. We need to design with &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything around us is designed&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; — from the seat you’re sitting on to the sheets of paper sitting in your printer. That sheet of paper, as simple as it may seem, was meticulously designed by someone just like me — someone just like you. The thickness of the paper was a design choice, allowing vendors to fit more in a pack and cutting the cost of production. The white color of the paper was a design choice — it is practical, and also conveys great emotion: that of having a clean slate. Paper has been designed and redesigned time after time since about the year &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;105 AD&lt;/span&gt; It was designed with love and care, with the single purpose of giving your content, be it art, text, or anything else, a place to &lt;em&gt;shine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paper was designed with love and care, with the single purpose of giving your content, be it art, text, or anything else, a place to &lt;i&gt;shine&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to design everything the way paper was designed. We need to value simplicity, typography, and color. We need to take color, shape, texture, and rhythm into careful consideration. We need to design honestly, transparently&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and with generous amounts of love and care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need to design honestly, transparently, and with generous amounts of love and care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I’m going to go ahead and present to you what I think are important principles of honest, transparent design. Following these principles won’t guarantee a beautiful, emotional design, but it will certainly help you gain a better insight into any design problem you might encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ambitious&quot;&gt;1. Ambitious&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great design is bold, rule-breaking, and ambitious. If we don’t break out of our niches or go against design trends, how will we ever innovate? Don’t be afraid of failure, either. Be fearless. Design something that nobody has ever thought of before — that’s the only way you can break the cycle of trend and become an innovator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ambitious design is also honest. It allows you to forget any predetermined notions about what you’re designing or who you’re designing for, thus allowing you to focus your mind on the design solution rather than just on the design problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;universal&quot;&gt;2. Universal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great design can be understood by anyone, regardless of what language they speak or what ideals they might have. Don’t focus your energy creating a design that will be understood by one section of your audience. Take a step back, look at the problem, and find a solution that will fit everyone’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a step back, look at the problem, and find a solution that will fit everyone&#39;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Universal design represents or results in products and environments that are usable by all people, to the greatest extent possible, without the need for adaptation or specialized design.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enlightened&quot;&gt;3. Enlightened&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great design is well-researched and rational. Let’s regress to the design of paper for a minute. Paper was designed to fit a simple need — recording events and history. Prior to paper and its cousin papyrus, man used chisel and stone to record history. While this was more permanent, it was found to be impractical and non-universal because it could not be erased or adapted. Thus, paper was born. Research then went into every design detail of paper, from the consistency of the pulp to the exact size of a sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-researched, rational, enlightened design gives the end-user or viewer the benefit of seeing and using a product that was carefully crafted to fit their exact needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adaptable&quot;&gt;4. Adaptable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great design is adaptable. It can be transformed and tweaked to fit the needs of people at present. Again, let’s regress to the design of paper. As I stated in point &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;No. 3&lt;/span&gt;, paper came out of a need for something better. It evolved from ideas that are as adaptable as they are timeless: writing and art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all began with cave drawings. Originally there was no language, and thus no need for writing. Cavemen merely needed to sketch things that they saw. Then came early language, and with it came carvings on stone slabs. Next came papyrus, as civilizations began to develop and languages expanded. And it slowly evolved into what we know as paper today as our needs and conditions changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything around us is designed. The thought, care, and love that we have for the things we use every day — our MacBooks, our iPhones, our clothes, and anything else — should be reflected in the things that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; design. Learn to sweat the details — the subtleties of your typography, the tint of your colors, and every other tiny detail in your design. &lt;strong&gt;Design with love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learn to sweat the details — the subtleties of your typography, the tint of your colors, and every other tiny detail in your design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put your whole heart and soul into designing an honest design — a design that is &lt;strong&gt;ambitious&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;universal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;enlightened&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;adaptable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/_dte&quot;&gt;Dan Eden&lt;/a&gt; put this perfectly on the homepage of &lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.me/&quot;&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ttimsmith&quot;&gt;Tim Smith’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theboldreport.net&quot;&gt;The Bold Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; did an excellent example of this, open-sourcing its code and design. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Tim Smith is also working on a &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; cool project appropriately named Open Source Design. &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensourcedesign.is&quot;&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicinterestdesign.org/glossary/&quot;&gt;the Public Interest Design Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/how-english-sounds-to-non-english-speakers</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/how-english-sounds-to-non-english-speakers"/>
    <title>How English Sounds to Non-English Speakers</title>
    <published>2013-10-18T14:11:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-18T14:11:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fascinating! I’ve always wondered what English might sound like to non-English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/napoleon-hill</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/napoleon-hill"/>
    <title>Napoleon Hill</title>
    <published>2013-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you think you are beaten, you are. If you think you dare not, you don’t. If you like to win, but you think you can’t, it is almost certain you won’t. If you think you’ll lose, you’re lost, for out in the world we find, success begins with a fellow’s will – it’s all in the state of mind. If you think you are outclassed, you are. You’ve got to think high to rise. You’ve got to be sure of yourself before you can ever win a prize. Life’s battles don’t always go to the stronger or faster man, but soon or late the man who wins is the man who thinks he can.” &lt;br /&gt; — Napoleon Hill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/starting-fresh</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/starting-fresh"/>
    <title>Starting Fresh</title>
    <published>2013-07-22T11:11:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-22T11:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, my Windows 7 PC of three years crashed. I lost three entire years worth of design files, school work, and photos. I lost music, programs, and emails. I lost everything — all my hard work and memories (both good and bad). At first, I was utterly devastated. But after I had exhausted all possible routes of recovering my files, I came to realize that stating of with a clean slate would do me more good than bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called my dad and told him that, after two years of whining about wanting a Mac, it was finally time to fulfill that dream. Two days later, we ordered my 13-Inch MacBooK Pro off the Apple website and requested store pickup. Keep in mind that this was only 45 minutes before the Apple Store closed. The drive from our house to the Apple Store is &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; about 45 minutes — we made it there in 35 (shh, don’t tell). After arriving at the Apple Store, the manager let me know that my computer won’t be ready for pickup for a few hours, but they close in five minutes. My dad, thinking quickly, interjected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s just buy another one in the store, and then I’ll ‘pick up’ and return the other computer tomorrow on my way home from work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks dad, that was wicked cool! So I walked out of the store that day a proud owner of a brand now MacBook Pro. I also had a fresh start — a clean slate — to be more productive and work harder than I ever had before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience opened open many doors for me. I learned a few valuable lessons, was introduced to the copywriter for a cool new startup called &lt;a href=&quot;http://widdle.it&quot;&gt;Widdle&lt;/a&gt;, was able to share &lt;a href=&quot;https://theguild.co&quot;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt; with a few people, and, most importantly, learned how to work hard for the things that I want or need. My new Mac has drastically changed the way I work, read, and browse. The vast spectrum of apps that are available for the Mac is breathtaking. From design apps to development apps; from reading apps to writing apps; from games to focus tools, and everything in between, these tools have increased my productivity and creativity tenfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress. Starting fresh without any files or programs has increased my productivity and has allowed me to see my work more clearly. With the $100 App Store gift card that I received for free with my Mac, I purchased tons of useful apps — but only the apps I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;. Nothing less, nothing more. This is a great way to start a new chapter in my life. I’m finally done seeing the thousands of errors thrown by Windows’ CMD whenever I tried running a Ruby Gem. I’m finally through struggling to run Photoshop and Sublime Text 3 at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m finally free from the shackles of Windows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My hard work is gone&lt;/strong&gt;, but I have a totally clean slate to create better work. I have a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it feels &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to a new computer, I just launched the finished redesign of my website, which you are currently viewing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/devinhalladay&quot;&gt;What do you think?&lt;/a&gt; You can read a bit more about this site in my about page under the “Colophon” section, or you can wait a few days until I blog about its creation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/design-over-style</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/design-over-style"/>
    <title>Design Over Style</title>
    <published>2013-03-05T09:06:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-05T09:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was browsing through the day’s Twitter feed, when I saw this brilliant Tweet by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/schneidertobias&quot;&gt;@schneidertobias&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…we need more web designers and less web stylists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dumbfounded. After hours of pondering the implications of Tobias’s statement, I sat down at my desk with a can of cold San Pellegrino and began writing down my interpretation in my journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-web-stylist&quot;&gt;What is a “web stylist”?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to give Tobias the credit of coining the term “web stylist,” but I will take credit for defining it (aren’t I so humble?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web stylist is someone who simply &lt;em&gt;styles&lt;/em&gt; the web. He or she doesn’t worry about content or hierarchy; form or function. All a web stylist &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; worries about is making the final product &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D4i7vS_UO4Q&quot;&gt;fluffy&lt;/a&gt; and pretty. Websites designed by a web stylist often lack strong usability, a cohesive organization pattern, and other essential design patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-a-web-designer&quot;&gt;What is a web designer?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web designer is a “web stylist” that gives &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/03/23/does-form-follow-function/&quot;&gt;function to form&lt;/a&gt;. A web designer’s workflow begins with an idea and ends with a beautiful &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt;* functional product. Content, usability, hierarchy, and all the other “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2008/08/05/7-essential-guidelines-for-functional-design/&quot;&gt;functional design&lt;/a&gt;” buzzwords are the some of the first and last things that enter a web designer’s mind while working on a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, a web designer gives beauty &lt;em&gt;function and &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/blog/designer-of-souls/&quot;&gt;soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the definitions out of the way, let’s explore the implications of Tobias’s statement and some methods of solving the “web stylist” dilemma that seems rampant in the web today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers need to put &lt;em&gt;design&lt;/em&gt; over &lt;em&gt;style&lt;/em&gt;. What does that mean? It simply means that before a designer can make a project beautiful, he/she must first consider what I like to call “&lt;em&gt;ACHOO&lt;/em&gt;” (pronounced &lt;em&gt;ah-choo&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;ccessibility - Easy use regardless of any physical disabilities.
&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ontent - Clear, concise text and easily identifiable images.
&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;ierarchy - Easy to distinguish the important from the insignificant.
&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;ptimization - Works in all major browsers and operating systems.
&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;ne Minute Rule - Given one minute of viewing time, what will a user remember about the site?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only after successfully going through and passing the &lt;em&gt;ACHOO&lt;/em&gt; can the designer move on to beautifying the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t merely &lt;em&gt;style&lt;/em&gt; the web, give the web &lt;em&gt;function&lt;/em&gt;. If every web designer put some more effort into recognizing the necessary function and fulfilling it before focusing on beauty, the web would be a much better place to browse; work; and, hopefully, play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I urge all of you to take some time to evaluate your standing with relationship of form and function, and if you discover that it is flawed, &lt;em&gt;remember to always ACHOO&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put &lt;em&gt;function&lt;/em&gt; over &lt;em&gt;form&lt;/em&gt;.
Put the &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; above &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Put &lt;em&gt;design&lt;/em&gt; over &lt;em&gt;style&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designer-of-souls</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designer-of-souls"/>
    <title>Designer of Souls</title>
    <published>2013-02-03T05:05:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-03T05:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As designers, I’m sure we can reach a general consensus that when web design, we design for the viewer. We use color theory, white space typography, and countless other elements of design (some of which we are not even aware that we are using) in order to convey a message or a feeling to the viewer.
But what is the secret to great design that successfully conveys those feelings or messages to the user?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As designers, I’m sure we can reach a general consensus that when web design, we design for the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably wondering, &lt;em&gt;“What the hell does that even mean? Is this guy crazy?”&lt;/em&gt; Well I can assure you that I am crazy, but that is beside the point.
When designing, you need to design not just with the user in mind, but with &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt; in mind. It’s important to remember that great design is not only concise beautiful, and creative; it is soulful. Let’s dive deeper into the &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; part of this and see what happens when we come out on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soul is a beautiful thing. This may sound crazy, but your soul is what makes thoughts and feelings &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;. I know that we have all seen a design, at one time or another, that just hits us straight in the soul. For me, that design is anything by &lt;a href=&quot;http://joncontino.com/&quot;&gt;Jon Contino&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven’t heard of Jon (what am I saying, of course you’ve heard of him!) then go check out some of his work and watch some videos about him. Jon pours his soul into everything he designs, and successfully conveys the desired message almost every time. &lt;em&gt;We all need to be a little more like Jon.&lt;/em&gt; We need to pour our soul into everything we design. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am a designer of souls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pour my heart and soul into every design I make. Sure, sometimes I make mistakes and the design doesn’t turn out the way it’s supposed to — but that’s okay. By using your soul to design rather than your brain, you can create a connection with the viewer that is stronger than your silly color theory and white space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in everything you design from this point onward, I want you to give your design a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working and writing all day, so this article may not be as eloquently written as you might have hoped — but I truly hope that you can take something away from this. I hope that you have learned that great design is not just pixels or ink, but rather the &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; that makes the design &lt;em&gt;special&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am a designer of souls.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/the-new-me</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/the-new-me"/>
    <title>The New Me</title>
    <published>2013-01-22T04:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-22T04:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My website has been reborn. My branding has been reborn. I have been reborn. &lt;em&gt;This is the new me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, finally publishing a post on a personal website that I’m proud to call my own. What prompted this change? &lt;em&gt;Lots of things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One month ago today I made some huge changes to my life. I am now working hard to balance school, design, family and friends in order to improve my quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is a very short blog post, but I’m in a last minute rush to push my new site (this one) live by 4:00 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site and its new design exemplifies my personality, my minimalist beliefs, and, most importantly, my love for design. I will be sharing reviews, interviews, and hastily-developed personal thoughts every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Info about the site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typeset in FF Tisa Web Pro and Proxima Nova, served by TypeKit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Published using Jekyll and GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handmade in three days using SublimeText 2 and Photoshop CS6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting a followup to this post in the next day or two explaining the “new me” and thanking all of the people that have supported me thus far in my still-budding career as a designer &amp;amp; developer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>