<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com"/>

  <title>Devin Halladay</title>
  <link href="http://devinhalladay.com"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://devinhalladay.com/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2014-04-30T21:08:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://devinhalladay.com</id>
  <author>
    <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    <email>devin@devinhalladay.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/devinhalladay</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/devinhalladay"/>
    <title>My Website</title>
    <published>2014-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;masthead&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-5 small-12 columns push-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;hr class=&quot;long&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;My Website&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;hr class=&quot;long&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;page-masthead large-5 small-12 pull-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;hr class=&quot;long&quot;&gt;
      A glimpse into the making of my site, and its continous evolution as my humble home on the web.
      &lt;hr class=&quot;long&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;large-10 small-12 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My website has always been a sacred place — a place where I can experiment, test, succeed, fail, and share. As a writer, it’s important to me that I have an outlet besides pen and paper to share some of my thoughts with the world. As a designer and a human being, that outlet needs to be beautiful and it needs to reflect who I am — this means it has to show my painstaking attention to detail, my love for typography, my unique mind, and my individualism. &lt;em&gt;It needs to feel like home.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;That’s what this website is to me — home&lt;/strong&gt;. It allows me to be free. Like any home, this website needs constant improvement and change to fit my ever-changing personality and tastes. Many of you know that I’m only 17 years old — and as I continue to grow older, my life grows more complicated. When my life is complicated, this website might be simplified to help me feel more at home again; or, when my life is simple, maybe I’ll rethink my website so that it compliments my life.
    &lt;br&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Whatever happens with this website in the future, it will always be my home on the Internet, and I will treat it with the respect and love that I give to my brick &amp;amp; mortar home — the same goes for every other project I work on, whether it be for a client or for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;wrap-grey&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-4 small-12 columns push-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Judging a Book by Its Cover&lt;/h3&gt;

      &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/urban-life-and-form.png&quot; title=&quot;Urban Life and Form&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;fluidbox&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/urban-life-and-form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Urban Life and Form&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of my favorite book covers. It gives the reader only what they &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to become intriqued in the book, and nothing more. Simple, but not too simple. Brilliant.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;large-6 small-12 columns pull-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        While I don&#39;t encourage the act of judging a book by its cover, I understand that many people do this without even realizing it (including myself). There&#39;s no avoiding that. But one thing I have learned through the past few iterations of my website is that the homepage is one of the most important pages on any website. I tried to make the homepage of this website simple and readable, like a book — but not so simple as to dissuade visitors from continuing on to other pages.
        &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;My goal with the homepage of this website is to give users just enough information and design so that they become interested in the site — just like a great book cover. This may seem like an obvious concept, but it&#39;s shocking how many designers don&#39;t understand this. I think of a book cover as a photograph of the contents of the book. Looking at a photo, you usually can&#39;t see much only see what the photographer &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; you to see. If you want to see more, you need to go to the location and see it for yourself — this is why photography is so intoxicating as an artform.
        &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Applying these principles to this website, I have been fairly successful in having visitors click through to other pages on my website — many of my visitors have viewed nearly every page on my website; and fifteen of those visitors in the past year have turned into clients.&lt;/strong&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-8 small-11 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In future iterations of this website, I&#39;ll probably try to adopt a new homepage concept that is truly akin to a book cover — no articles, no links, just a small snapshot of me and my ability as a designer, writer, and human being. I&#39;ll cross that bridge when the time comes, though.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote large-8 small-11 columns large-offset-3 small-offset-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I think of a book cover as a photograph of the contents of the book. Looking at a photo, you usually can&#39;t see much only see what the photographer wants you to see. If you want to see more, you need to go to the location and see it for yourself — this is why photography is so intoxicating as an artform.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-10 small-12 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;The Typography&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        I&#39;m obsessed with typography, so much so that it&#39;s almost unhealthy — &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;. Typography is one of the most powerful, and most complicated, aspects of design; and it&#39;s equally as important to me as a writer. Typography can convey so much emotion in a design. Helvetica, a bold, steril font, can make a design feel strong; Neutra Display can make a design feel elegant; or if you set type in Arial, it might feel cheap and flimsy, like cardboard.
        &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;With this in mind, I chose three incredibly strong, yet personable typefaces from &lt;span class=&quot;serif-sc&quot;&gt;H&amp;amp;Co.&lt;/span&gt;: Sentinel ScreenSmart, Whitney ScreenSmart, and Mercury ScreenSmart (also the small-caps variants of Whitney SSm and Mercury SSm). Headers and most display text are set in Sentinel; Blockquotes, pullquotes, image captions, and other tertiary text are set in Whitney; And most body text is set in Mercury (although lately I&#39;ve been switching between Sentinel and Mercury every few weeks to suit my mood).
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;figure class=&quot;img-caption-overlay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/type-sample.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Type samples.&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-overlay&quot;&gt;Left to right: Mercury Bold, Whitney Bold, Sentinel Bold&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;large-10 small-12 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;The Grid&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        This year one of my goals is to learn to understand the power of the grid, and to learn to use it properly to harness that power. I&#39;ve come a long way, but there&#39;s still so much to learn.
        &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I use &lt;span class=&quot;serif-sc&quot;&gt;ZURB&lt;/span&gt; Foundation for grids on this site. Originally I planned on using Susy, but it was a little too complicated for me at the time because I didn&#39;t fully understand how grids work in design. Foundation has been an essential tool in the creation of this website, and has allowed me to focus on the design rather than focusing on coding the layouts.
        &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Take this case study, for example. It would have taken me tons of time to code an editorial page like this without the help of Foundation! Foundation has allowed me to experiment with layouts without worrying about ruining other parts of my site by changing site-wide CSS.
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote large-8 small-11 columns large-offset-3 small-offset-1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Typography is one of the most powerful, and most complicated, aspects of design; and it&#39;s equally as important to me as a writer.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-10 small-12 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Constraints and Restraint&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; print design. One of my passions as a web designer is bringing elements of print design to the web — the typography, the grids, and the beauty of constraints and restraint. With that love for print in mind, I have tried to create an environment similar to a newspaper: constrained by a simple grid, limited to a minimal color palette, but restricted only by the limits of my imagination and ingenuity as a designer. This has made designing and developing my website manageable while still leaving room for expansion or reduction.
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;figure class=&quot;img-caption-overlay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/good-idea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Type samples.&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption-overlay&quot;&gt;Contraints and restraint: because it&#39;s just a good idea.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;wrap-grey&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-5 small-11 single-text-column push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Static, and Electric&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Content management systems frustrate me. Too many of them have too many features — and the ones I love, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://siteleaf.com&quot;&gt;Siteleaf&lt;/a&gt;, don&#39;t have the features that I need for my site. That&#39;s why, with this latest iteration of my site I&#39;m using Jekyll. It doesn&#39;t have any fluff — in fact, it&#39;s fairly barebones as a static site generator — but it gives me the ability to change the source code or develop plugins that suit my workflow and my website.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;sans light&quot;&gt;
        Side note: I absolutely adore Siteleaf. If I didn&#39;t need more extensibility, I&#39;d still be using it for my website. I use it for most other static websites I create, though. Go sign up and give it a try! You won&#39;t regret it.
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-4 small-11 columns pull-2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/jekyll-and-hyde.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll and Hyde&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;fluidbox&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/jekyll-and-hyde.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll and Hyde&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;I just &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the type on this poster!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row full-width&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;large-10 small-11 push-1 columns&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Constant Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It&#39;s inevitable that the website you see before you will undergo constant change while it&#39;s online. Seriously, I&#39;m antsy and I&#39;m a perfectionist so it has to be this way to keep me sane. Despite the constant change, this website will continue to be a rock for me to fall back on when I am in need of a visible change in my philosoophy. It will continue to be my home, and it will always showcase my ideas, my work, and my love for everything design.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h3 class=&quot;light&quot;&gt;I hope you enjoy it as much as I do.&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/ui</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/ui"/>
    <title>UI Design</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/reads.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Weekly reads widget for The Guild&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/reads.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Weekly reads widget for The Guild&quot; alt=&quot;Weekly reads widget for The Guild&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/mail_widget.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mail Widget UI&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/mail_widget.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mail Widget UI&quot; alt=&quot;Mail Widget UI&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/live_support_chat.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Live support chat UI&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/live_support_chat.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Live support chat UI&quot; alt=&quot;Live support chat UI&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/mt-hyde.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mr. Hyde iPad app UI&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/mt-hyde.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mr. Hyde iPad app UI&quot; alt=&quot;Mr. Hyde iPad app UI&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/the-ministry-of-print</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/the-ministry-of-print"/>
    <title>The Ministry of Print</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/modern_influence.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Modern Influence poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/modern_influence.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Modern Influence poster&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Influence poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Modern Influence&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/synesthesia.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Synesthesia poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/synesthesia.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Synesthesia poster&quot; alt=&quot;Synesthesia poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Synesthesia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/11/disruption.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Disruption poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/11/disruption.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Disruption poster&quot; alt=&quot;Disruption poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disruption&lt;/strong&gt;: A poster I designed to explore the disruption of waves and the uniformity that such seemingly disruptive forces can create in their idenetically intricate curves.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/perception.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Perception poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/perception.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Perception poster&quot; alt=&quot;Perception poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception&lt;/strong&gt;: An exploration of the human experience. The way we as a society perceive things has become increasingly skewed along with the advancement of technology and our subsequent avoidal of reality. &lt;strong&gt;With this poster I tried to capture our skewed perception.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/wander_small.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Those Who Wander poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/wander_small.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Those Who Wander poster&quot; alt=&quot;Those Who Wander poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those Who Wander&lt;/strong&gt;: This poster began with me experimenting with blackletter typography. I had been reading Tolkien&amp;#8217;s &lt;i&gt;The Fellowship of the Ring&lt;/i&gt; at the time and this quote form the novel really resonated with me. I decided to take my passion for lettering to the next level and created this poster.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oceania.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Oceania poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oceania.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Oceania poster&quot; alt=&quot;Oceania poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oceania&lt;/strong&gt;: I didn&amp;#8217;t have any specific reasons for creating this one. &lt;strong&gt;I just had an idea and acted on it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/royale_poster.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Royale poster&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/royale_poster.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Royale poster&quot; alt=&quot;Royale poster&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Royale&lt;/strong&gt;: The first poster I ever made. I created this one for a new boutique design agency called &lt;strong&gt;Royale&lt;/strong&gt; that I will be starting soon with a few good friends.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/print-design</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/print-design"/>
    <title>Misc. Print Design</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/11/cards.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Personal business cards&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/11/cards.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Personal business cards&quot; alt=&quot;Personal business cards&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My personal business cards&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal here was to futher explore and hone my understanding of typography by using the classic Neue Haas Grotesk and a limited color palette.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/article_page_spread.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Article spreads for The Guild magazine&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/article_page_spread.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Article spreads for The Guild magazine&quot; alt=&quot;Article spreads for The Guild magazine&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Article spread for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theguild.co&quot;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a new design magazine that I have been working on in my spare time for the past half a year or so.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/logomark</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/logomark"/>
    <title>Logo + Marks</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-3&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/squire.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Squire Logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2014/03/squire.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Squire Logo&quot; alt=&quot;Squire Logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/guild_shot.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Guild&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/guild_shot.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Guild&quot; alt=&quot;The Guild&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/2014/02/royal_courier.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Royal Courier logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2014/02/royal_courier.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Royal Courier logo&quot; alt=&quot;Royal Courier logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/eagle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;USA logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/eagle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;USA logo&quot; alt=&quot;USA logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/s-mark.jpg&quot; title=&quot;S Lettermark&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/s-mark.jpg&quot; title=&quot;S Lettermark&quot; alt=&quot;S Lettermark&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/crown-loading.gif&quot; title=&quot;Loading Crown Logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/crown-loading.gif&quot; title=&quot;Loading Crown Logo&quot; alt=&quot;Loading Crown Logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/bear-logo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bear Logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/bear-logo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bear Logo&quot; alt=&quot;Bear Logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oddball.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Oddball Logo and Mark&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oddball.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Oddball Logo and Mark&quot; alt=&quot;Oddball Logo and Mark&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oddball-lettermark.gif&quot; title=&quot;Oddball Lettermark&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/oddball-lettermark.gif&quot; title=&quot;Oddball Lettermark&quot; alt=&quot;Oddball Lettermark&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/devin-logo.gif&quot; title=&quot;Personal Lettermark&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/devin-logo.gif&quot; title=&quot;Personal Lettermark&quot; alt=&quot;Personal Lettermark&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/guild-logo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Guild logo&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/guild-logo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Guild logo&quot; alt=&quot;The Guild logo&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/lettering</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/lettering"/>
    <title>Lettering</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-3&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/d-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;D&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/d-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;D&quot; alt=&quot;D&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/2-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;2&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/2-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;2&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/s-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;S&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/s-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;S&quot; alt=&quot;S&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/amp-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/amp-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; alt=&quot;Ampersand&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/amp-letter-2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/amp-letter-2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; alt=&quot;Ampersand&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/d-letter-2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;D&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/d-letter-2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;D&quot; alt=&quot;D&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/gothic.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Gothic lettering&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/gothic.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Gothic lettering&quot; alt=&quot;Gothic lettering&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/c-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Calligraphy C&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/c-letter.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Calligraphy C&quot; alt=&quot;Calligraphy C&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/kick.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Kick script&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/kick.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Kick script&quot; alt=&quot;Kick script&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/never-say-die.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Never Say Die script&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/never-say-die.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Never Say Die script&quot; alt=&quot;Never Say Die script&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/quasar.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Quasar font&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/quasar.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Quasar font&quot; alt=&quot;Quasar font&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/action.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Action vintage type&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/action.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Action vintage type&quot; alt=&quot;Action vintage type&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/the-end.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The End script&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/the-end.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The End script&quot; alt=&quot;The End script&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/work/illustration</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/work/illustration"/>
    <title>Illustration</title>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-1 large-block-grid-3&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/books.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Book stack illustration&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2014/02/books.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Book stack illustration&quot; alt=&quot;Book stack illustration&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/hammeraxe.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hammer &amp;amp; Axe&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/hammeraxe.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hammer &amp;amp; Axe&quot; alt=&quot;Hammer &amp;amp; Axe&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/sword.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sword&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/sword.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sword&quot; alt=&quot;Sword&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/beef.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Butcher guide for beef cuts&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/beef.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Butcher guide for beef cuts&quot; alt=&quot;Butcher guide for beef cuts&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/revolver.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Revolver&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/revolver.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Revolver&quot; alt=&quot;Revolver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/lion.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lion&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/lion.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lion&quot; alt=&quot;Lion&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/owl_eagle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Owl&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/owl_eagle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Owl&quot; alt=&quot;Owl&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/toucan.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Toucan&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/toucan.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Toucan&quot; alt=&quot;Toucan&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/ampersand.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/ampersand.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ampersand&quot; alt=&quot;Ampersand&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/grand_canal.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Grand Canal&quot; data-fluidbox data-no-instant&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://devinhalladay.com/uploads/2013/10/grand_canal.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Grand Canal&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Canal&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/a-manifesto-for-quality-thought</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/a-manifesto-for-quality-thought"/>
    <title>A Manifesto for Quality Thought</title>
    <published>2014-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No amount of thought can change anything unless ideas are shared and acted upon. If you censor yourself, you’ll never know what impact your thoughts can have on the&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thought is the essence of life. Do not be afraid to be alone with your thoughts. When you take time away from the influence of society to be alone with your thoughts, you might learn more about yourself than you ever thought&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong opinions are encouraged and welcomed, but they are nothing without facts to support them. Before you form an opinion of someone or something, do your research to make sure that your opinion is&amp;nbsp;justifiable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regardless of where you are or who you interact with, in today’s society you must develop an empathy for all creeds, classes, ways of life, and for all people in&amp;nbsp;general.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beware of stagnation—it prevents learning. You need to learn to always adapt to situations as they arise, thus learning something from each precious moment of your time here on&amp;nbsp;Earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take nothing for granted. You must learn to question everything. Quality thought is not only measured by your ability and willingness to explore new ideas and domains but also by your ability to apply new ideas to the&amp;nbsp;familiar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality thought is nothing without a voice to speak it. Thinking and speaking go hand-in-hand. Always share your thoughts with&amp;nbsp;others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thoughts are best when shared and added to. In the same way that you need to speak your mind, you must also have the ability to listen to the thoughts that others share; and you must have the willingness to learn from their&amp;nbsp;ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality thought does not exist solely in the realm of intellect. The power of thought lies in your ability to make connections between those thoughts and the society we live in today. Quality thought needs to have some bearing on your life or on the lives of those around&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You cannot have quality thought without passion. Your thoughts cannot bloom without inspiration. Look for inspiration where you do not expect it, as inspiration often takes unexpected&amp;nbsp;forms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designed-with-love</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designed-with-love"/>
    <title>Designed with Love</title>
    <published>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;I love design. Its uncanny ability to make any person feel a wide range of emotions is absolutely fascinating. As designers, we hold the power of emotion in our hands — we can use color theory to evoke emotions, whitespace to draw attention, and so much more. That fact makes it clear that we need to pay attention to every pixel and give an equal amount of care to every single detail in what we are designing, in order to honestly and efficiently harness emotion. We need to design with &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Everything around us is designed—from the seat you&amp;#8217;re sitting on to the sheets of paper sitting in your printer. That sheet of paper, as simple as it may seem, was meticulously designed by someone just like me — someone just like you. The thickness of the paper was a design choice, allowing vendors to fit more in a pack and cutting the cost of production. The white color of the paper was a design choice — it is practical, and also conveys great emotion: that of having a clean slate. Paper has been designed and redesigned time after time since about the year 105 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;A.D.&lt;/span&gt; It was designed with love and care, with the single purpose of giving your content, be it art, text, or anything else, a place to &lt;em&gt;shine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paper was designed with love and care, with the single purpose of giving your content, be it art, text, or anything else, a place to &lt;i&gt;shine&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We need to design everything the way paper was designed. We need to value simplicity, typography, and color. We need to take color, shape, texture, and rhythm into careful consideration. We need to design honestly, transparently, and with generous amounts of love and&amp;nbsp;care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need to design honestly, transparently, and with generous amounts of love and&amp;nbsp;care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I&amp;#8217;m going to go ahead and present to you what I think are important principles of honest, transparent design. Following these principles won&amp;#8217;t guarantee a beautiful, emotional design, but it will certainly help you gain a better insight into any design problem you might&amp;nbsp;encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;Ambitious&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great design is bold, rule-breaking, and ambitious. If we don&amp;#8217;t break out of our niches or go against design trends, how will we ever innovate? Don&amp;#8217;t be afraid of failure, either. Be fearless. Design something that nobody has ever thought of before — that&amp;#8217;s the only way you can break the cycle of trend and become an&amp;nbsp;innovator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ambitious design is also honest. It allows you to forget any predetermined notions about what you&amp;#8217;re designing or who you&amp;#8217;re designing for, thus allowing you to focus your mind on the design solution rather than just on the design&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;Universal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great design can be understood by anyone, regardless of what language they speak or what ideals they might have. Don&amp;#8217;t focus your energy creating a design that will be understood by one section of your audience. Take a step back, look at the problem, and find a solution that will fit everyone&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take a step back, look at the problem, and find a solution that will fit everyone&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Universal design represents or results in products and environments that are usable by all people, to the greatest extent possible, without the need for adaptation or specialized&amp;nbsp;design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;Enlightened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great design is well-researched and rational. Let&amp;#8217;s regress to the design of paper for a minute. Paper was designed to fit a simple need — recording events and history. Prior to paper and its cousin papyrus, man used chisel and stone to record history. While this was more permanent, it was found to be impractical and non-universal because it could not be erased or adapted. Thus, paper was born. Research then went into every design detail of paper, from the consistency of the pulp to the exact size of a&amp;nbsp;sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-researched, rational, enlightened design gives the end-user or viewer the benefit of seeing and using a product that was carefully crafted to fit their exact&amp;nbsp;needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;Adaptable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great design is adaptable. It can be transformed and tweaked to fit the needs of people at present. Again, let&amp;#8217;s regress to the design of paper. As I stated in point No. 3, paper came out of a need for something better. It evolved from ideas that are as adaptable as they are timeless: writing and&amp;nbsp;art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all began with cave drawings. Originally there was no language, and thus no need for writing. Cavemen merely needed to sketch things that they saw. Then came early language, and with it came carvings on stone slabs. Next came papyrus, as civilizations began to develop and languages expanded. And it slowly evolved into what we know as paper today as our needs and conditions&amp;nbsp;changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Everything around us is designed. The thought, care, and love that we have for the things we use every day — our MacBooks, our iPhones, our clothes, and anything else — should be reflected in the things that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; design. Learn to sweat the details — the subtleties of your typography, the tint of your colors, and every other tiny detail in your design. &lt;strong&gt;Design with&amp;nbsp;love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learn to sweat the details — the subtleties of your typography, the tint of your colors, and every other tiny detail in your&amp;nbsp;design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Put your whole heart and soul into designing an honest design — a design that is &lt;strong&gt;ambitious&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;universal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;enlightened&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;adaptable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/how-english-sounds-to-non-english-speakers</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/how-english-sounds-to-non-english-speakers"/>
    <title>How English Sounds to Non-English Speakers</title>
    <published>2013-10-18T14:11:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-18T14:11:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fascinating! I&amp;#8217;ve always wondered what English might sound like to non-English&amp;nbsp;speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/napoleon-hill</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/napoleon-hill"/>
    <title>Napoleon Hill</title>
    <published>2013-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dquo&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;If you think you are beaten, you are. If you think you dare not, you don’t. If you like to win, but you think you can’t, it is almost certain you won’t. If you think you’ll lose, you’re lost, for out in the world we find, success begins with a fellow’s will – it’s all in the state of mind. If you think you are outclassed, you are. You’ve got to think high to rise. You’ve got to be sure of yourself before you can ever win a prize. Life’s battles don’t always go to the stronger or faster man, but soon or late the man who wins is the man who thinks he can.&amp;#8221; &lt;br&gt; —Napoleon&amp;nbsp;Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/starting-fresh</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/starting-fresh"/>
    <title>Starting Fresh</title>
    <published>2013-07-22T11:11:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-07-22T11:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, my Windows 7 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; of three years crashed. I lost three entire years worth of design files, school work, and photos. I lost music, programs, and emails. I lost everything — all my hard work and memories (both good and bad). At first, I was utterly devastated. But after I had exhausted all possible routes of recovering my files, I came to realize that stating of with a clean slate would do me more good than&amp;nbsp;bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called my dad and told him that, after two years of whining about wanting a Mac, it was finally time to fulfill that dream. Two days later, we ordered my 13-Inch MacBooK Pro off the Apple website and requested store pickup. Keep in mind that this was only 45 minutes before the Apple Store closed. The drive from our house to the Apple Store is &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; about 45 minutes — we made it there in 35 (shh, don&amp;#8217;t tell). After arriving at the Apple Store, the manager let me know that my computer won&amp;#8217;t be ready for pickup for a few hours, but they close in five minutes. My dad, thinking quickly,&amp;nbsp;interjected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s just buy another one in the store, and then I&amp;#8217;ll &amp;#8216;pick up&amp;#8217; and return the other computer tomorrow on my way home from&amp;nbsp;work!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks dad, that was wicked cool! So I walked out of the store that day a proud owner of a brand now MacBook Pro. I also had a fresh start — a clean slate — to be more productive and work harder than I ever had&amp;nbsp;before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience opened open many doors for me. I learned a few valuable lessons, was introduced to the copywriter for a cool new startup called &lt;a href=&quot;http://widdle.it&quot;&gt;Widdle&lt;/a&gt;, was able to share &lt;a href=&quot;https://theguild.co&quot;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt; with a few people, and, most importantly, learned how to work hard for the things that I want or need. My new Mac has drastically changed the way I work, read, and browse. The vast spectrum of apps that are available for the Mac is breathtaking. From design apps to development apps; from reading apps to writing apps; from games to focus tools, and everything in between, these tools have increased my productivity and creativity&amp;nbsp;tenfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress. Starting fresh without any files or programs has increased my productivity and has allowed me to see my work more clearly. With the $100 App Store gift card that I received for free with my Mac, I purchased tons of useful apps — but only the apps I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;. Nothing less, nothing more. This is a great way to start a new chapter in my life. I&amp;#8217;m finally done seeing the thousands of errors thrown by Windows&amp;#8217; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CMD&lt;/span&gt; whenever I tried running a Ruby Gem. I&amp;#8217;m finally through struggling to run Photoshop and Sublime Text 3 at&amp;nbsp;once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;m finally free from the shackles of Windows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My hard work is gone&lt;/strong&gt;, but I have a totally clean slate to create better work. I have a fresh&amp;nbsp;start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it feels &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designer-of-souls</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/designer-of-souls"/>
    <title>Designer of Souls</title>
    <published>2013-02-03T05:05:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-03T05:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
      <uri>http://devinhalladay.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As designers, I&amp;#8217;m sure we can reach a general consensus that when web design, we design for the viewer. We use color theory, white space typography, and countless other elements of design (some of which we are not even aware that we are using) in order to convey a message or a feeling to the&amp;nbsp;viewer.
But what is the secret to great design that successfully conveys those feelings or messages to the&amp;nbsp;user?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As designers, I’m sure we can reach a general consensus that when web design, we design for the&amp;nbsp;viewer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The secret is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;re probably wondering, &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;What the hell does that even mean? Is this guy crazy?&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt; Well I can assure you that I am crazy, but that is beside the&amp;nbsp;point.
When designing, you need to design not just with the user in mind, but with &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt; in mind. It&amp;#8217;s important to remember that great design is not only concise beautiful, and creative; it is soulful. Let&amp;#8217;s dive deeper into the &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; part of this and see what happens when we come out on the other&amp;nbsp;side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soul is a beautiful thing. This may sound crazy, but your soul is what makes thoughts and feelings &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;. I know that we have all seen a design, at one time or another, that just hits us straight in the soul. For me, that design is anything by &lt;a href=&quot;http://joncontino.com/&quot;&gt;Jon Contino&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven&amp;#8217;t heard of Jon (what am I saying, of course you&amp;#8217;ve heard of him!) then go check out some of his work and watch some videos about him. Jon pours his soul into everything he designs, and successfully conveys the desired message almost every time. &lt;em&gt;We all need to be a little more like Jon.&lt;/em&gt; We need to pour our soul into everything we design. But I&amp;nbsp;digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am a designer of&amp;nbsp;souls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pour my heart and soul into every design I make. Sure, sometimes I make mistakes and the design doesn&amp;#8217;t turn out the way it&amp;#8217;s supposed to — but that&amp;#8217;s okay. By using your soul to design rather than your brain, you can create a connection with the viewer that is stronger than your silly color theory and white&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in everything you design from this point onward, I want you to give your design a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working and writing all day, so this article may not be as eloquently written as you might have hoped — but I truly hope that you can take something away from this. I hope that you have learned that great design is not just pixels or ink, but rather the &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; that makes the design &lt;em&gt;special&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am a designer of souls.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are&amp;nbsp;you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>