<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Devin Halladay</title>
  <subtitle>Journal</subtitle>
  <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal</id>
  <link href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal"/>
  <link href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Devin Halladay</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Lessons Learned</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/lessons-learned/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/lessons-learned/</id>
    <published>2015-08-24T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id="img-alt-titleyou-cant-always-have-what-you-need-srcassetsimages201508wantneedjpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" title="You can't always have what you need." src="/assets/images/2015/08/wantneed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've learned a few important lessons this summer that I thought I'd share—mostly for myself, but hopefully they will help you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There will always be people who will do shitty things to you. Sometimes those people will be the people who are...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="img-alt-titleyou-cant-always-have-what-you-need-srcassetsimages201508wantneedjpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" title="You can't always have what you need." src="/assets/images/2015/08/wantneed.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've learned a few important lessons this summer that I thought I'd share—mostly for myself, but hopefully they will help you, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There will always be people who will do shitty things to you. Sometimes those people will be the people who are closest to you, sometimes they will be strangers. No matter who they are, there will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; be more shit for you to deal with. That's life. But life does go on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depression is the worst thing. Ever. Hands-down. I have felt a misery and a helplessness that I can't describe in words. It hurts, and you will feel that pain deeply in ever inch of your body and mind. But you can get through it. Keep people you like close to you, keep yourself busy, and don't get caught in thought traps. Just stay alive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you need to play with fire, play with fire. You may get burned, you may burn all your bridges, but in the end you'll learn how to play with fire more safely the next time around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take risks. Overload yourself with work if that's what you need to do. Turn down job offers because you think something better will come along. &lt;strong&gt;Tell people the truth, even if the truth is too painful to say aloud.&lt;/strong&gt; And, most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;tell yourself the truth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can't always have what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can't always have what you need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life is overwhelming, but you need to force yourself to take things a day at a time. Don't bundle days together, because if you do you will forget that eventually your problems and pain will fade and make way for new problems and pain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Louie Clip" href="https://vimeo.com/98735680"&gt;Misery is wasted on the miserable.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need to let go. Move on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes you need to just open the floodgates and let your emotions and thoughts consume you if only for a little while.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just because you mean everything you say doesn't mean everyone else means what they say.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's not your fault.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You do not have to be &lt;a href="http://www.poets.org/poetsorg/poem/ozymandias"&gt;Ozymandias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing is the most important thing you can do. You have a gift; use it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more creative you are, the more predisposed you are to depression and anxiety disorders. You view the world differently than everyone else, which means you see what is wrong with the world and that makes you vulnerable. Be strong, and don't lose faith.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Failure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/failure/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/failure/</id>
    <published>2015-02-23T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-23T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could let my failures surround me and I could submit to that nagging feeling in the back of my head that I'm not good enough, that I can't be good enough, that I won't be good enough. But instead of dwelling on thoughts that might not be true, I...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could let my failures surround me and I could submit to that nagging feeling in the back of my head that I'm not good enough, that I can't be good enough, that I won't be good enough. But instead of dwelling on thoughts that might not be true, I'm looking at this from a different angle. Sure, I've failed. I've lost clients and proposals, disappointed people, disappointed myself, and and I've come up short in a lot of aspects of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few hours ago I asked myself why I'm failing so terribly at so many things. After a bit of introspection, I realized that I've been putting myself out there more than usual. I've been seeking out and accepting opportunities that are well outside my comfort zone. Some of these ventures into the unknown have been great personal successes; some of them have been tremendous flops. From both the successes and the failures, though, I can learn something. I can look at what I did wrong or right, and why I failed or succeeded. I can move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on I'm going to be a bit more conservative with my decisions because, frankly, failure sucks; and all this seething disillusionment with not meeting my own expectations is becoming too much to bear all at once. Next time I'm faced with a tremendous challenge, I may not be prepared, but at least I'll know how to handle the situation to increase my odds of success.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What's the secret?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/whats-the-secret/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/whats-the-secret/</id>
    <published>2015-02-20T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of people these days are looking to live a life that doesn't interfere with the status quo. Others are looking for ways to get rich quick on the internet.  They ask "what's the secret?  how can I launch x-for-x in a week's time without...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of people these days are looking to live a life that doesn't interfere with the status quo. Others are looking for ways to get rich quick on the internet.  They ask "what's the secret?  how can I launch x-for-x in a week's time without any money, without hiring anyone, and without proper knowledge? how can I do this without failing a million times before I become successful?" Want to know the truth? It's not pleasant: there is no secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get rich and popular by cutting corners, by writing click-bait articles on your Medium.com blog, by criticizing others to make yourself look like a hero, you can do that. Go ahead. But the odds are that you won't make any lasting impact. You'll get your moment in the spotlight, but that light will fade away more quickly than it sparked to life. People will forget you and your haphazard idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to make a great product, run a great business, gain the love and trust and admiration of people you don't even know, you can't just look for a secret. There are no shortcuts on the path you're going to take. You're going to work hard, then work harder, then work so hard you forget what it's like to relax. You're going to stress out and stress out some more. You're going to live and breathe your scrappy little venture because you think you can make a difference in the world. You won't love it every day because it's tough, but you'll keep moving. You will miss opportunities and fail when you think you're about to succeed. You'll probably spend a lot of sleepless nights wondering what the hell you're doing wrong. But you'll never give up. You'll persist and when your gut feeling is to give up you're going to grab a coffee, sit down, and get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when you least expect it, you're going to realize something. Every day you've been working, you've gained a new follower, made a couple bucks, and sweated the details. Your users/customers/followers have noticed.  Now seemingly overnight you feel like magic because you've done something magical: you've worked like mad to do something  mad, and every second has paid off. You've done something that matters, and you're prouder than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="meta"&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@moloneymike"&gt;Mike Moloney&lt;/a&gt; for his editing help.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Change</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/on-change/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/on-change/</id>
    <published>2015-02-13T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-13T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Keep a record of everything in your life—the big, the small, the bad, the good. One day ten years from now, five years from now, hell, even one year from now, you'll be able to look back at the way things were and see that all the shit you went through...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Keep a record of everything in your life—the big, the small, the bad, the good. One day ten years from now, five years from now, hell, even one year from now, you'll be able to look back at the way things were and see that all the shit you went through to get to this point was entirely worth it. You will learn from your mistakes, you will see growth. You will surprise yourself. You will realize that not everything happens for a reason but that everything you did, said, and felt has led you to this little apotheosis. You will feel triumphant for one glorious moment; but that moment will be fleeting. You will change again, then look back, undefeated; and then you will face change and defeat again, and again, and again. But it will all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Matters</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/what-matters/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/what-matters/</id>
    <published>2015-02-06T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-06T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's not what you do  when the stars shine bright  on the paved road  that matters, but what you do  when you're down in the dust,  when the earth swirls up around you  and you feel life's hands  around your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's not what you do  when the stars shine bright  on the paved road  that matters, but what you do  when you're down in the dust,  when the earth swirls up around you  and you feel life's hands  around your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ten Reminders</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://devinhalladay.com/journal/reminders/"/>
    <id>http://devinhalladay.com/journal/reminders/</id>
    <published>2015-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-05T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Halladay</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay humble.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never stop learning or experimenting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never become complacent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You're good at what you do, but there are always ways to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your options open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don't focus on the negative.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give yourself a break.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People matter...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay humble.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never stop learning or experimenting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never become complacent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You're good at what you do, but there are always ways to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your options open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don't focus on the negative.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give yourself a break.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People matter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don't forget who you are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Live a life you're proud of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
